ROSO ANTONIO PEÑARANDA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(312) 749-7884

ROSOPENARANDA@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB.COM/ROSOPENARANDA

PROFILE

Fullstack web developer, focused on creating high quality software following practices such as: clean architecture, SOLID and POO

Experience designing, modeling and implementing software from modeling diagrams to code and database implementation, ending with deployment in clouds such as AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean.

I also have knowledge in Software Architecture, Relational Database Design, Docker, Kubernetes, Information Security and ethical hacking.

SKILLS

- Relational database design and development.
- Web Development: ReactJs,
- Rests API Development:
 ExpressJS, NestJs, Spring Boot,
 Ruby on Rails
- Graphql
- SQL, PI/PGSQL: PostgresSQL, MySql, Oracle, Sql Server
- NoSql: MongoDB, Reddis, CosmosDB
- POO: Java, JS, Python, Ruby, TS
- computer security:Pentesting and ethical hacking
- Networks
- Docker, Kubernetes
- **SO**: Debian, Ubuntu y MacOS
- Cloud: Azure (AZ-900), AWS, Digital Ocean

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR BACKEND DEVELOPER

SWEATWORKS | MAY 2021 -

- Custom Software Development, APIs REST, Microservices.
- Stack: React, Redux, Redux-Sagas, NestJS, PostgreSQL, Sql Server, CosmosDB, Docker, Kubernetes, SqlServer, Azure Insight, Azure Service Bus, Azure Blob Storage, Jest, AWS, SQS, AWS - Lambda, eclipse mosquitto

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SOUTHWORK | FEB 2021 - APR 2021

- Custom Software Development
- Stack: React, Redux, Redux-Sagas, NestJS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, .Net, Jest, Microservices

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

CICLOSPECIAL | AUG 2020 -FEB 2021

- Development of the company's new eccommerce, integration and automation of the activities of the different operational areas of the company.
- Stack: React, Redux, Redux-Sagas, NestJS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Kubernetes, GrapQL, Microservices, Jest, RabitMQ

FREELANCE DEVELOPER

FEB 2019 - JAN 2020

- Website development and email layout for netwellth.us.
- API development, bug fixes in web app for veinte.net

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

DATEGEEK | JAN 2018 - JAN 2019

- Web application, mobil app and Api for claims management and case tracking
- Stack: React, React Native, MaterialUI, PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express, Ruby on Rails

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

BRANDO & ASOCIADOS | FEB 2018 - DEC 2018

- Web application and Api for claims management and case tracking
- Stack: React, MaterialUI, PostgreSQL, Node, Express, Python

INFORMATION SYSTEMS MANAGER

RED TECNOLÓGICA 20 C.A. | MAR 2015 - JAN 2017

- Custom application development
- Stack: Java, Ruby, PHP, HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL MySQL, SQL Server
- dependents: 6

ROSO ANTONIO PEÑARANDA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(312) 749-7884

ROSOPENARANDA@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB.COM/ROSOPENARANDA

SKILLS

- Relational database design and development.
- Web Development: ReactJs, Redux
- Rests API Development: ExpressJS, NestJs, Spring Boot
- Graphql
- SQL, Pl/PGSQL: PostgresSQL, MySql, Oracle, Sql Server
- NoSql: MongoDB, Reddis, CosmosDB
- POO: Java, JS, Python, Ruby, TS
- computer security:Pentesting and ethical hacking
- Networks
- Docker, Kubernetes
- SO: Debian, Ubuntu y MacOS
- Cloud: Azure (AZ-900), AWS, Digital Ocean
- Queue: RabitMQ, Azure Services Bus, AWS SQS, Eclipse Mosquito

EXPERIENCE

SYSTEMS AND TECHNOLOGY MANAGER

AEROCASILLAS VNZ | SEP 2012 - JAN 2015

- Development of the company's invoicing and parcel tracking system.
- Stack: HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, PHP, MySql, Java
- dependents: 4

EDUCATION

DEVOPS

MUNDO E | FEB 2022 - NOV 2022

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE

EAN UNIVERSITY | OCT 2021 - DEC 2021

COMPUTER ENGINEERING

SIMÓN BOLÍVAR UNIVERSITY | 2008 - NOT FINISHED APPROVED 202 OF 205 CREDITS

AWARDS AND PERSONAL PROJECTS

BEESOFT LABS MEDELLIN 2021, 2022

VOLUNTEER AS A TYPESCRIPT PROGRAMMING MENTOR

CODE MENTORING MEDELLIN

GROUP OF DEVELOPERS FOCUSED ON SHARING KNOWLEDGE ABOUT SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT.

#MEDELLINPYTHON 2020

VOLUNTEER MENTOR IN A PROJECT OF THE MAYOR'S OFFICE OF MEDELLIN, TO TEACH PROGRAMMING TO THE POPULATION FREE OF CHARGE.

PROYECT CCS212.COM

CENTRALIZE IN A PUBLIC DATABASE THE INFORMATION OF REGISTRIES, NOTARIES, UNIVERSITIES AND MINISTRIES OF THE CITY OF CARACAS, THE SYSTEM HAS A WEB PAGE DEVELOPED IN REACT.JS (CCS212.COM) AND A MOBILE APP IMPLEMENTED IN FLUTTER, WITH ALL THE INFORMATION AVAILABLE WITHOUT THE NEED OF AN INTERNET CONNECTION.

RISK ANALYSIS OF THE KOHA SYSTEM OF THE SIMON BOLIVAR UNIVERSITY LIBRARY.

RISK ANALYSIS CARRIED OUT IN THE CENTRAL LIBRARY OF THE SIMÓN BOLÍVAR UNIVERSITY

HACKING CHALLENGE 2017

I WAS PART OF THE CHAMPION TEAM AND RECEIVED THE AWARD FOR THE MOST CREATIVE HACK.